<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Malte S. Kurz</title>
    <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Malte S. Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019-2024 Malte S. Kurz</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications in Academic Journals</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Papers</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/manuscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/manuscripts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/software/</guid>
      <description>Python package DoubleML (&amp;ldquo;Double Machine Learning in Python&amp;rdquo;) with P. Bach, V. Chernozhukov and M. Spindler    [ PyPI, conda-forge, Package source, Documentation, Bug reports ]
 R package DoubleML (&amp;ldquo;Double Machine Learning in R&amp;rdquo;) with P. Bach, V. Chernozhukov and M. Spindler   [ CRAN, Package source, Documentation, Bug reports ]
 Python package DoubleML-Serverless (&amp;ldquo;Distributed Double Machine Learning with a Serverless Architecture&amp;rdquo;)  [ Package source, Bug reports ]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refereeing</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/refereeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/refereeing/</guid>
      <description> Computational Statistics &amp;amp; Data Analysis Deutsche Bundesbank Discussion Papers Electronic Journal of Statistics Journal of Banking &amp;amp; Finance Journal of Statistical Software  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Exercise Sessions    Term Course     Summer 2018 (Univariate) Time Series Analysis, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Winter 2017&amp;#x2215;18 Probability Theory and Inference I, Department of Statistics, LMU   Summer 2017 (Univariate) Time Series Analysis, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Winter 2016&amp;#x2215;17 Probability Theory and Inference I, Department of Statistics, LMU   Summer 2016 (Univariate) Time Series Analysis, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2015 (Univariate) Time Series Analysis, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2014 (Univariate) Time Series Analysis, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2014 Econometric Analysis of Tick Data, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2013 Introduction to Financial Databases for Bachelor Theses, Institute for Capital Markets and Corporate Finance, LMU   Winter 2010&amp;#x2215;11 Introduction to Financial Accounting, Chair of Accounting, Universität Konstanz   Winter 2009&amp;#x2215;10 Introduction to Financial Accounting, Chair of Accounting, Universität Konstanz    Seminars    Term Course     Winter 2016&amp;#x2215;17 MA-Seminar: Financial Econometrics, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2015 BA-Seminar: Quantitative Risk Management, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Winter 2014&amp;#x2215;15 BA-Seminar: Financial Econometrics, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2014 BA/MA-Seminar: Financial Econometrics, Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU    Thesis Supervisions    Term Thesis     Winter 2021&amp;#x2215;22 A Double Machine Learning Approach to Model Acommodation Prices in the Sharing Economy (MA Thesis), Chair for Statistics, Faculty of Business Administration, University of Hamburg   Summer 2021 Causal Reinforcement Learning: Theory and Implementation (MA Thesis), Chair for Statistics, Faculty of Business Administration, University of Hamburg   Summer 2018 Multivariate Volatility Modeling for Crypto Currencies (MA Thesis), Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2017 Diversifikationseffekte in der Portfoliooptimierung (MA Thesis), Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Winter 2016&amp;#x2215;17 Conditional and Partial Copulas: Approximations Based on Mixture Distributions (BA-Thesis), Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU   Summer 2015 Asymmetric Correlations in Financial Returns (BA-Thesis), Chair of Financial Econometrics, LMU    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/talks/</guid>
      <description>Jan 25, 2022 Seminar Series of the Analytics, Insights and Measurement (AIM) &amp;ndash; Data Science Team at Google Presentation (virtual): &amp;ldquo;DoubleML &amp;ndash; A State-of-the-Art R/Python Framework for Causal Machine Learning&amp;ldquo;   Jan 20, 2022 Microeconometrics for Big Data (Lecture, TUM School of Management, TU Munich), Munich, Germany Guest-Lecture (virtual): &amp;ldquo;DoubleML &amp;ndash; A State-of-the-Art R/Python Framework for Causal Machine Learning&amp;ldquo;   Jul 09, 2021 useR!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MalteKurz.github.io/home/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>